

Marcos Ramirez

Full Stack Web Developer

0

San Diego, California



+1 (210) 262 1266



mrcrmz@gmail.com

Skills

| Technical

PHP

Javascript

HTML

CSS / SCSS

Symfony

Doctrine ORM

MySQL Databases

Git Version Control

| Other Skills

Algolia InstantSearch.js
Copper CRM API
Microsoft Excel / Google Sheets
Zapier
PersistIQ
Spanish

Education

| Bachelor's Degree, | Computer Science, Spanish St Edward's University Graduated May 2019

Achievements

| Honors Program St Edward's University 2015 - 2019

Profile

A Texas-born web developer living and working in San Diego, I have two years professional experience working with PHP(Symfony), JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and MySQL databases. A recent graduate from St. Edward's University in Austin, I am excited to gain more experience in web development as well as design. I am adept with both backend and frontend development, but I am looking to focus on frontend. I'm a fast learner and would especially love to work with technologies such as React and Vue.

Work Experience

The Venue Report | Nov 2017 - Present

Web Developer

June 2019 -Present

The Venue Report is an online marketplace for venues and event spaces that features promotional media by way of a blog, as well as a messaging feature to connect users with venue owners. I was hired to work on the Symfony web application from an internship position after graduation in 2019. As a fulltime employee, I took on larger projects than those I had worked on before.

- Completely replaced the site's search functionality (elasticsearch) with Algolia's InstantSearch.js that combined both keyword and location-based search for venues and blog content.
- Monitored search KPIs such as "no results rate" to make informed improvements on the InstantSearch implementation. Brought down no results rate from an average of 13% to 8%.
- Leveraged Copper CRM's API and webhooks to collect venue submission form data and automate portions of the sales process, including emails and invoicing.
- Worked with team members to QA development work and release to production environment.
- Communicated code updates to non-technical team members and stakeholders through release emails.

Junior Developer - Intern

November 2017 - May 2019

The Venue Report's development team at the time was based in Austin, Texas, where I was hired as an intern as I completed by bachelor's degree. As an intern I:

- Replaced the site's main navigational header with new designs.
- Created multiple promotional landing pages for the business as well as paying clients
- Addressed bugs and issues across the site from small styling issues to more complicated backend issues that affected other team members' work flow.
- Undertook project to add new values for status field and update all business listings
 on the website to accurately reflect business status, resulting in a reduction of
 operational overhead and improved client and customer satisfaction.
- Learned much about the Symfony framework as well as web development in general.